ZHIHAO XIA

zxia@adobe.com \$ https://likesum.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests include computer vision, computational photography, and machine learning. I am particularly interested in building methods that can recover different aspects of visual appearance (geometry, light, colors, etc.) from images, by using both physics-based reasoning and machine learning.

EDUCATION

Washington University in St. Louis

Sep 2017 - Jun 2021

Ph.D. in Computer Science & Engineering

Advisor: Ayan Chakrabarti

Sep 2013 - Jun 2017

University of Science and Technology of China

B.S. in Computer Science, School of the Gifted Young

Honor: National Scholarship (Top 2%)

EXPERIENCE

Adobe Jun 2021 - Present

Research Scientist II CA, USA

· Using computational photography and machine learning to build next-gen camera for mobile devices.

· Lead a small team of researchers to develop novel computational photography algorithms.

Google Research
Research Intern

May 2020 - Dec 2020
WA, USA

· Worked with Supreeth Achar and Jason Lawrence on face relighting and normal estimation under challenging visible light environments by supplementing a near-infared image.

Adobe Research May 2019 - Aug 2019

Research Intern CA, USA

- · Worked with Federico Perazzi, Michaël Gharbi, Kalyan Sunkavalli on Basis Prediction Networks.
- · Research was transferred into products and published in CVPR 2020.

Washington University in St. Louis

Sep 2017 - Jun 2021

Research Assistant

MO, USA

- · Member of WashU vision and learning group directed by Prof. Ayan Chakrabarti.
- · Computer Vision, Computational Photography and Deep Learning.

King Abdullah University of Science and Technology

Jan 2017 - May 2017

Visiting Student Researcher

Jeddah, SAU

· Worked with Prof. Xin Gao on recognition of polyadenylation signal (PAS) in human and mouse genes with CNN.

National University of Singapore

July 2016 - Nov 2016

Visiting Student Researcher

Singapore

· Worked with Prof. Richard Ma on investigating Internet topology with Multiple Hidden Markov Chains.

- 1. Haiwen Feng, Zheng Ding, **Zhihao Xia**, Simon Niklaus, Victoria Abrevaya, Michael J. Black, Xuaner Zhang. "Explorative Inbetweening of Time and Space", *ECCV*, 2024.
- 2. Zheng Ding, Xuaner (Cecilia) Zhang, **Zhihao Xia**. "Restoration by Generation with Constrained Priors", *CVPR*, 2024.
- 3. Goutam Bhat, Michaël Gharbi, Jiawen Chen, Luc Van Gool, **Zhihao Xia**. "Self-Supervised Burst Super-Resolution", *ICCV*, 2023.
- 4. Zheng Ding, Xuaner (Cecilia) Zhang, **Zhihao Xia**, Lars Jebe, Zhuowen Tu, Xiuming Zhang. "DiffusionRig: Learning Personalized Priors for Facial Appearance Editing", *CVPR*, 2023.
- 5. Ke Wang, Michaël Gharbi, He Zhang, **Zhihao Xia**, Eli Shechtman. "Semi-supervised Parametric Real-world Image Harmonization", *CVPR*, 2023.
- 6. Ethan Tseng, Yuxuan Zhang, Lars Jebe, Xuaner (Cecilia) Zhang, **Zhihao Xia**, Yifei Fan, Felix Heide*, Jiawen Chen* "Neural Photo-Finishing", SIGGRAPH Asia, 2022.
- 7. Ilya Chugunov, Yuxuan Zhang, **Zhihao Xia**, Xuaner (Cecilia) Zhang, Jiawen Chen, Felix Heide. "The Implicit Values of A Good Hand Shake: Handheld Multi-Frame Neural Depth Refinement", *CVPR*, 2022 (Oral).
- 8. Zhihao Xia, Jason Lawrence, Supreeth Achar. "A Dark Flash Normal Camera", ICCV, 2021.
- 9. **Zhihao Xia**, Michaël Gharbi, Federico Perazzi, Kalyan Sunkavalli, Ayan Chakrabarti. "Deep Denoising of Flash and No-Flash Pairs for Photography in Low-Light Environments", *CVPR*, 2021.
- 10. **Zhihao Xia**, Federico Perazzi, Michaël Gharbi, Kalyan Sunkavalli, Ayan Chakrabarti. "Basis Prediction Networks for Effective Burst Denoising with Large Kernels", *CVPR*, 2020.
- 11. **Zhihao Xia**, Patrick Sullivan, Ayan Chakrabarti. "Generating and Exploiting Probabilistic Monocular Depth Estimates", *CVPR*, 2020 (Oral).
- 12. **Zhihao Xia** and Ayan Chakrabarti. "Identifying Recurring Patterns with Deep Neural Networks for Natural Image Denoising", WACV, 2020.
- 13. **Zhihao Xia** and Ayan Chakrabarti. "Training Image Estimators without Image Ground-Truth", NeurIPS, 2019 (Spotlight)
- 14. **Zhihao Xia**, Yu Li, Bin Zhang, Yuhui Hu, Wei Chen and Xin Gao. "DeeReCT-PolyA: a robust and generic deep learning method for PAS identification", *Bioinformatics*, 2018.
- 15. Yu Sun, **Zhihao Xia** and Ulugbek S. Kamilov. "Efficient and accurate inversion of multiple scattering with deep learning", *Optics express* 26(11): 14678-14688, 2018.

SKILLS

Python: Numpy, Tensorflow, PyTorch. C/C++. Matlab

SERVICE

- Reviewer for IJCV, TIP, CVPR, ICCV, IJCAI, WACV
- Assistant to Instructor, WashU Fall 2018 CSE 559A: Computer Vision. Developed and held recitation lectures, assisted with grading, staffed office hours to assist students
- Co-organizor: WashU CS Graphics, Vision, and Imaging Seminar, Fall 2019 and Spring 2020